Ahmed Nadeem

Software Engineer

+92 336 6443449 ahmed210899@gmail.com https://github.com/vhmvd https://www.linkedin.com/in/vhmn/ Lahore, PK

SUMMARY

I have 2 years of Android app development experience at Dubizzle Labs with first hand experience in many other technologies as well. I am a self motivated engineer with a product first approach, dedicated to crafting top quality solutions and ready to excel in my next challenge.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Lahore, PK

Dubizzle Labs 02/2023 - Present

Dubizzle Group owns and operates bespoke classifieds portals in emerging market of online portals, primarily in the MENA, South Asia and Southeast Asia regions.

- · Developed Dubai Transactions feature. (Historical property rental and purchase trends in Dubai)
- Developed the Filter V2 experience for Bayut. (Real time inventory based filter)
- · Implemented Kotlin Flows and coroutines and fixed performance critical bottlenecks.
- · Improved the Popular Properties feature of Bayut by showing dynamic property types based on selected location.
- Improved the Nearby Locations feature of Bayut by showing locations based on property count.
- · Improved data layer and added domain layer.

Associate Software Engineer

Lahore, PK

Dubizzle Labs 06/2022 - 02/2023

- Developed the Map V2 experience for Bayut. (Clustering based on zoom level)
- · Developed Property History feature on compose.
- · Revamped the login/registration for Bayut.
- · Migration of modules from Java to Kotlin.

Intern

Mission-Critical Communication LLC

06/2021 - 01/2022

- · Use case research and product design.
- · Responsible for cloud and infrastructure management.

Intern
Easy2Employ LLC
09/2021 - 12/2021

- · Worked on research and tweaking of Al model.
- · Developed SIAMESE network for scoring the CV.
- · Data cleaning and pre-processing.

SKILLS

Kotlin, Java, Jetpack, Android Studio, Git, OOP, Data Structures, Elasticsearch, GCP, AWS, REST, Algolia, MVVM, MVI, SOLID, Design Patterns, Firebase

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

Topi, PK

Ghulam Ishaq Khan Institute of Science & Technology

08/2018 - 06/2022